

Nikita Buevich

Product manager



Profile

Hello! My name is Nikita. I'm experienced and reliable product and project manager, combineing skills of product and business management and technical background of front-end developer.

I'm happy to work with smart, open-minded people and to use modern technologies and methodologies. I like to propose and implement hypotheses, influence the development of a project, design a product, plan development paths, experiment, implement new opportunities, discuss new features come up with ways out of hopeless business situations, analyse.

I have:

- Data-driven and outcome focused mindset. Analytical mind, ability to catch trends and draw conclusions based on numbers
- Forward-thinking and taking the initiative to anticipate the needs of team
- · Ability to take responsibility and be accountable for results
- · Ability to critically analyse the success (or un-success) of my solutions and iterate
- Excellent communications and interpersonal skills, empathy and ability to collaborate and communicate within all levels of the company, clients and contractors
- Good sense of design
- Technical background of frontend developer
- · Good written & verbal communication skills in English (Upperintermediate now, but progressing)

I can:

- Form and maintain a product development roadmap based on a deep understanding of new customers' needs and wants, collect and analyse their requirements and product feedback, make datadriven decisions about the direction to grow
- Analyse product metrics to define a better approach in delivering products with superior quality and with highly desired features set
- Keep up to date and prioritise features in the product backlog
- Monitor competitors in an assessment analysis of the strengths and weaknesses, review competitor's products

Contacts

+7 909 421 6222 / Russia nikitabuevich@gmail.com @nbuevich / Telegram

Date / place of birth 15.11.1992 Russia, Rostov-on-Don

Links

Personal website Facebook **Twitter**

Skills

Product management Agile Project Management Knowledgeable in UI/UX Web Development

Hobbies / Interests

Travelling. Investment and trading. Politics. Black and white film photography. MTB, climbing, snowboard, wakeboard, surf. Good movies, smart books. Listening jazz. Drinking good wine and chinese tea, eating tasty food.

Languages

Russian / Native English / Upper-intermediate

- Define product features, write clear detailed requirements, based on data, customer development and product expertise
- Lead team (managed different teams 3-20 members) and mentor colleagues
- Facilitate communication throughout the development process inside the company, including engineering and design teams
- · Manage projects delivery based on agile methodologies

Most experienced in industries: fintech, logistics, B2C services. Also interested in gaining experience in: crypto, web3, B2B services.

Employment History

Application development manager at Accenture

December 2020 — April 2022 (1 year 5 months)

I worked on an internal project of a bank from the TOP-5 of Russia. The project was connected with identification of risks and lending to legal entities. There were my main responsibilities here:

- · Development process management
- Estimation of terms and resources for fulfilling project tasks
- Planning and coordination of the development team
- Collection, analysis and formation of technical requirements
- · Interview accompaniment, onboarding and registration of employees
- · Prevention and timely resolution of critical situations
- · Preparation of reports and documentation

Product owner at LPR

December 2019 — December 2020 (1 year)

I worked in LPR as product owner part-timely. What I've done here:

- I have helped to assemble a team
- I mentored junior project/product manager and raised him up to a strong middle
- I established key road-map points and prioritised milestones
- · I worked with stakeholders and investors
- I analysed product feedback and requests
- I supervised delievery processes and project management
- I was engaged in election of outsource SEO and data-parsing teams and managed interaction with them

Product manager at <u>TradingView</u>

October 2018 - May 2019 (8 months)

In TradingView I worked as product manager, but also combined functions of project manager.

- Established key road-map themes. Determined which features to add to the road-map
- · Led product team meetings, scrum meetings
- · Managed backlogs and prioritised technical work
- Wrote user stories and defined requirements for design and engineering teams. Produced feature specifications. Drafted release notes for product launches
- · Collaborated with design, engineering and marketing teams
- Monitored and optimised release cycle processes
- Worked with internal teams and stakeholders to generate ideas.
 Identified ideas that aligned with strategy. Explained why certain ideas were prioritised and others were not
- · Analysed product feedback and requests

Product manager / Frontend architect at <u>GraphGrail</u> (MySmartChat)

January 2018 – August 2018 (8 months)

I came to MySmartChat (child project of GraphGrail) as contractor to help to choose suitable technologies, develop architecture of front-end and to make MVP. But the idea of project fascinated me and I stayed in it until the end.

After the core of prototype and UI-kit were developed, I counseled our HRs in front-end developers recruitment, interviewed. Then I mentored junior developers, realised code-review, controlled code-style and code quality.

I have taken part in a product launch as product manager. The main part of my job was behavior analysis of early adopters. I conducted user interviews, collected and analysed feedback. Wrote user stories, defined requirements for engineering team, generated and tested ideas, based on collected data.

Also, important thing was customer on-boarding, delivering product demos for new features — I captured short videos of functionality usage, described features and trained our support team and first users.

Besides this, I helped to search for investors and took part in negotiations.

In addition, we had no designer in team, so I made design prototypes too.

Frontend consultant at AvtoTO

October 2016 – January 2018 (1 year 3 months)

I worked in AvtoTO as remote front-end consultant. The task was to make a redesign of the online store.

Developed scope assessment, established key road-map themes. Staff recruitment counseling (designer, front-end developers) and interviewing. Supervised UI/UX design development. Helped to choose technologies, developed architecture of front-end and UI-kit. Mentored front-end developers, realized code-review, code-style and code quality control. Set up business processes.

Web developer at **Vezet Vsem**

April 2015 – August 2017 (2 years 4 months)

Worked as front-end developer, using such technologies as JS, React+flux, ES6, webpack, HTML, SCSS, BEM, jQuery. Closely collaborated with design team.

Also took part in generating and explanation of priority of ideas, analysed product feedback and requests, was interested in business case justification.

When I got more experience, started to mentor junior developers and make code review.

Project manager at Plan B

September 2014 – January 2015 (1 year 4 months)

I worked as a partner with Plan B studio. I was responsible for the support of existing clients.

- Established key road-map themes. Determined which features to add to the road-map
- Managed backlogs and prioritised technical work
- Monitored and optimised release cycle processes
- Wrote user stories and defined requirements for design and engineering teams. Produced feature specifications. Draed release notes for product launches
- Worked with internal teams and stakeholders to generate ideas.
 Identified ideas that aligned with strategy. Explained why certain ideas were prioritised and others were not
- Analysed product feedback and requests
- Negotiated with clients
- · Searched for contractors

CPO at 100% Sports

November 2012 - November 2013 (1 year)

I worked in a sport/extreme stuff shop "100% Sports". I was a head of the online store of this company and was responsible for the quality of service and for business metrics. I had a team of 5-10 managers and other staff. During 1 year of my work the project's revenue increased 4 times.

Own Projects

Owner at <u>357gramm</u> (online tea-store)

July 2020 — Present

Co-owner at Katuha (active recreation club)

October 2017 - May 2018 (8 months)

A small travel company that organises holidays in the mountains (ski/snowboard, MTB, rafting, etc).

- Business strategy development; development and formalisation of business processes; financial planning
- · Marketing, SMM
- Team management (marketers, content-managers, tourism instructors, managers)
- Tours organisation (negotiation with hotels, transport companies, tourism instructors, etc)

Co-owner / CTO at "Dvigaidelo" (web-studio)

February 2014 – April 2015 (1 year 2 months)

Together with a partner marketer we organised the small web studio. I was responsible for all aspects of business, connected with product development. During the year we have successfully implemented about 10 projects.

It was our first experience in business. Project has died because of financial problems (crisis of 2014) and our marketing mistake that we made a big bet on word mouth.

Education

Bachelor Degree in Applied Math and Computer Science at <u>Southern Federal University</u>, Rostov-on-Don

September 2009 – June 2013

Assistant translator in Math and Computer Science at Southern Federal University, Rostov-on-Don

September 2011 - May 2013



Scrum for team

June 2021

GoPractice, Data-driven growth and product management online training

2020

<u>Product Mindset</u>, Program for the development of product thinking

February 2019 – April 2019

Academic art course at Art studio "Kolorit"

September 2005 - May 2009



References available upon request